Finding Aid for the Actors' Gang Records PASC-M.0319
UCLA Library Special Collections
Actors' Gang records
circa 1981
UCLA Library Special Collections
Actors' Gang (Theater ensemble)
PASC-M.0319
1 unknown (20 boxes)
The collection consists of the records of the Los Angeles theater company, The Actors' Gang. Included in the collection are production records, business papers, scripts and assorted materials pertaining to the theater company founded by Tim Robbins. The collection is in the midst of being processed. The finding aid will be updated periodically.
Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9961651533606533
Historical Note
The Actors' Gang is one of Los Angeles' most enduring theatre ensembles. Founded in 1981 by a group of renegade theatre artists, the Gang's mission is to create bold, original works for the stage and daring reinterpretations of the classics.
Over the course of our first 20 years the company has produced 68 plays and won over 100 awards, winning acclaim for their interpretations of Shakespeare, Bruchner, Brecht, Moliere, Aeschylus, Ibsen and Chekhov, while developing in workshop new plays that address the world today through a prism of satire, popular culture and raucous stagecraft.
Through co-productions, The Actors' Gang presented the West Coast Premiere of Eric Bogosian's "Suburbia" with the Namaste Theatre Company, Roger Guenver Smith's "A Huey P. Newton Story," Danny Hoch's "Jails, Hospitals, Hip Hop" with Center Theatre Group, and "Medea/Macbeth/Cinderella" with The Cornerstone Theatre Company. The Actors' Gang has toured with productions as the US representative at the Edinburgh Festival and to New York's Public Theatre with "Carnage, A Comedy"; with "The Imaginary Invalid" to the Rushmore Festival in New York, and in 2001 saw "Bat Boy, A Musical," developed at the Actors' Gang, won the Lucille Lortel and Outer Critics award for best new musical Off-Broadway in New York.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of production files, financial papers, scripts, and other assorted materials pertaining to the Los Angeles theater company.
The collection is organized into the following series:
Missing Title
Series 1. Financial Papers
Series 2. Production Files
Series 3. Development
Series 4. Clippings
Series 5. Unprocessed Materials
Theatrical companies -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archival resources.; Actors' Gang (Theater ensemble) -- Archives
- Financial Papers, Series 1.
  - Unprocessed Payroll Files, 2001-2003 (Box 1)
  - Unprocessed Credit Card Deposits (Box 2)
  - Unprocessed Payroll Files, 2001-2003 (Box 2)
  - Unprocessed invoices, 1994-1999 (Box 5)
  - Unprocessed invoices, 1994-1999 (Box 8)
- Production Files, Series 2.
  - The Seagull (Box 3)
- Unprocessed Materials, Series 5.
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 3)
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 4)
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 6)
  - Pitches (unprocessed), 1999 (Box 7)
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 9)
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 10)
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 11)
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 12)
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 13)
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 14)
  - Assorted Materials (unprocessed) (Box 15)